

艾怡華

EVA VIRGINIA ARÉVALO RIVARA

HSINCHU CITY, 300 · TAIWAN · 93.EVAR@GMAIL.COM

Passionate Machine Learning Researcher striving to incorporate machine learning to the workflow of real-world tasks to expedite the process and render it more efficient. Hands-on experience with state-of-the-art NLP models (BERT) and implementing deep learning models (Tensorflow/PyTorch) for NLP applications; as well as more traditional supervised and unsupervised learning tools. Acquainted with performing classification and more general heuristic tasks through Genetic Algorithms and Pattern Recognition techniques. Experience crawling and processing datasets from Social Media platforms (Twitter). Fundamental understanding of Parallel Programming.

EDUCATION

NATIONAL TSING HUA UNIVERSITY

September 2018 - Present

MS. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

HSINCHU CITY, TAIWAN

Research work performed under the guidance of Prof. Chen Yi-Hsin. Focused on the application of Machine Learning techniques to detect Manic Episodes in Bipolar users in Social Media Platforms.

GPA: 4.27

NATIONAL TSING HUA UNIVERSITY

September 2014 - June 2018

BS. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

HSINCHU CITY, TAIWAN

NATIONAL TAIWAN NORMAL UNIVERSITY

September 2013 - August 2014

INTENSIVE MANDARIN STUDIES

TAIPEI CITY, TAIWAN

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

C, C++, Python, Java, SQL, MySQL, MATLAB, Arduino, Verilog

MACHINE LEARNING & DEEP LEARNING

ΑI

- Clustering (kmeans/DBSCAN)
- ✓ PCA / TSNE
- Classification / Linear Regression
- ▼ Time Series
- Genetic Algorithms (GA)
- Pattern Recognition

- Tensorflow / Keras /
 Tensorhub
- Pytorch
- CNNs, RNNs, LSTMs, GANs
- Deep contextual representations (ELMo, BERT)

WEB DEVELOPMENT

- HTML5/CSS/ JavaScript
- ✓ NodeJs / Flask
- React / Bootrstrap
- MySQL / PostGreSQL / mongoDB
- Amazon Web Services
 (AWS) EC2, S3, RDS
 Services
- Docker
- Web visualizations with d3.js & Neo4j

MISCELLANEOUS

- Parallel Programming
- CUDA Programming

WORK EXPERIENCE

NATIONAL TSING HUA UNIVERSITY

September 2019 - January 2020

TEACHER ASSISTANT

HSINCHU CITY, TAIWAN

Teacher Assistant for the Data Mining: Concepts, Techniques, and Applications course, offered by Prof. Chen Yi-Hsin, National Tsing Hua University, Institute of Information Systems and Applications (ISA 5810, Fall 2019).

NATIONAL TSING HUA UNIVERSITY

February 2019 - June 2019

TEACHER ASSISTANT

HSINCHU CITY, TAIWAN

Teacher Assistant for the Data Structures course offered by Prof. Chen Yi-Hsin, National Tsing Hua University, Computer Science Department (CS 2351, Spring 2019).

EMBASSY OF CANADA

July 2013 - August 2013

IMMIGRATION PROGRAM REGISTRY CLERK

GUATEMALA CITY, GUATEMALA

Assisting and expediting the processing of visa applications. Managing and maintaining the storing of visa applications. Performing general office administration duties.

June 2013 - June 2013

EMBASSY OF CANADA

RECEPTIONIST AND SWITCHBOARD OPERATOR

GUATEMALA CITY, GUATEMALA

Greeting, welcoming and announcing visitors to the Embassy of Canada in Guatemala. Receiving and forwarding incoming calls. Providing information and guidance. Performing general administration duties.

TELUS INTERNATIONAL

July 2013 - August 2013

CUSTOMER SERVICE REPRESENTATIVE (FRENCH LANGUAGE DIVISION)

GUATEMALA CITY, GUATEMALA

Customer Service Representative for online game platform Zynga. Assisting and providing information to customers.

LANGUAGES & SOFT SKILLS

LANGUAGES

- Spanish Native Proficiency
- French Native Proficiency
- **English** Native Proficiency
- Chinese Professional Working Proficiency
- Japanese Beginner Proficiency

SOFT SKILLS

- Strong sense of responsibility
- ✓ Aim for Efficiency and Excellency
- Good Organizational Skills
- Adaptability
- Proactive
- Pragmatic approach

LICENCES & CERTIFICATES

LEGAL TRANSLATION CERTIFICATE (ENGLISH-SPANISH)

December 2012

MINISTRY OF EDUCATION, GUATEMALA (MINEDUC)

GUATEMALA CITY, GUATEMALA

Authorized by the Ministry of Education, Guatemala to provide legal translation and interpretation services (Spanish-English).

evar_resume.github.io is maintained by EvaArevalo.

This page is hosted by GitHub Pages.

View on GitHub